So, our fun little exercise this shouldn't take as long.
I'm going to push up my branch to the O4 exercise branch,
and your task that you choose to accept it
is to migrate everything from the routes
and into file-based routing.
So, I kept this one a little bit on the shorter side
because, you know, again, it's kind of like a fun thing to kind of get used to,
and if it's kind of easier for you to play with on your own also.
So, let's go ahead and just let's migrate the whole thing, shall we?
So, when I'm doing the migration for something like this,
something actually the first thing I actually want to emphasize here
is actually that you might notice that these two approaches
are actually co-existing right now.
There is the pages approach, and you technically have some views being manually defined.
I do think this is a big philosophy that I've always enjoyed about view
and kind of its community is that it doesn't try to force you one way or the other,
and it basically lets you, I mean, to kind of what we talked about earlier in this workshop,
kind of composes the things that make sense to you.
Because I don't know if some of you got to the challenges part,
but this, not found doing wildcards is a little bit,
it's actually, you actually have to look in the docs for this,
it's not incredibly intuitive.
And so, I have, I mean, there's a world where some people like,
because this is just easier for them to understand,
they'll configure some of the routes still manually,
because maybe they also have some custom things they want to do,
maybe programmatically, that doesn't fit the file based routing,
because that's usually what I hear when people criticize file based routing,
and they're like, I have this one edge case that doesn't apply to that,
and it's like, that's cool, but for 95% of the things,
file based routing, it's great.
So, this is my reminder to you that, like,
while I'm going to migrate everything over,
you certainly don't have to, and more importantly,
to manually define your routes in the future,
it is really just a step away by just adding something inside of this route configuration.
Okay, so that's it.
Let's go ahead and move on.
Okay, first thing first, reflection, I'll drop that one first.
So, I'll move that over,
and then I'll just call it reflection,
and then we'll get rid of it inside of the routes page here.
Boom, save, I think that's good.
So, we're going to test it though.
We always test our things.
All right, that's up.
We go to reflection.
Great.
It's working.
All right, moving on.
Let's just do the sandbox page, because we can.
Yes, move.
And then we'll just rename that sandbox.
And then inside of our routes, we delete the sandbox page here.
Check it.
Yep, there's our sandbox page.
Okay, keep going.
Let's do settings next.
So, drop that over there.
Settings, delete from here.
There we go.
And then click settings.
Hey, there's our settings.
Everything's so works.
Great.
All right. Now, the kudigra.
All right.
So, the planner section.
Let's take a look at how we intended this to be routed.
So, the planner page itself is.
Looks like it's just slash planner.
So, one way we could do this.
So, you saw that earlier.
For slash tasks, I did like an index under the folder.
I might, this should work the way I think it does,
which is that you can still just make this like just planner like this.
And so,
now that that's planner,
we should be able to then come in.
Oh wait, I didn't delete the other record.
Okay.
So, now, planner should be here.
And there you go.
Planner renders.
That's expected.
Okay, here is then the tricky part.
So, now you have this week, as well as this ID here.
So, what we need to do here is we need to do a folder for week.
And then we create a, well, I actually take it back.
I don't need to create.
I just need to drag week detail page in here.
And then swap out the name for a square bracket ID.
This should be okay.
About to find out if I'm wrong.
Okay.
So, now we have this.
So, just refresh it real quick.
And then we're going to, let's see, look at the week itself.
Page not found.
What happened?
Failed to resolve that shouldn't be the reason.
Okay.
So, let's debug this together.
Let's see.
We have it.
Oh.
Don't we need to put it in a planner folder or something like that?
To match the original way that it was.
Oh.
Yeah, you're totally right.
I got ahead of myself.
Let me undo this real quick.
I guess I thought I created it.
I might, I will tell you in my head.
I created a planner folder.
I clearly did not.
You were 100% right.
So, that means week needs to be nested under here.
There you go.
Planner week ID.
All right.
Now let's try this again.
Oh, sorry.
Let me delete this.
Yes.
Oh.
All right.
This is a fun little tip bit.
Okay.
Tip here.
So, you may have noticed we have a lot of broken paths.
Do people, I don't know if you noticed this pattern I was using.
This, the at symbol or people familiar with this.
Okay.
Great.
For those who are not, this is something that comes from the meat config.
And it's actually an alias.
So, this is not magic.
There's something you can configure.
And it basically says, hey, for these paths, whenever you prefix it with at,
I want you to start from the root directory and go straight into source.
And so this makes it a lot easier to deal with moving things between directories
because you know that everything is always going to start at the source.
Although granted, I'm not sure why it's so yelling at me.
But one thing at a time.
Okay.
Now that that's done, let's refresh.
And then that did not work.
Planner is good.
Week did not happen.
Okay.
What's the problem here?
So, I assume this is what you are mentioning.
So, what I'm going to do now is we're going to take a look at the type router to see what is generating.
So, we see that there's planner here.
Planner planner here.
Planner week ID here.
Prem ID true ID, prem false.
So, that seems like it's sound.
To do do planner week.
And then this is also, see, this is,
As soon as this is planner week, we'll find out.
H, wait.
Why is this an H3?
This seems suspicious.
H3 card title.
I have a guess.
This is in our planner.
No weeks available.
It's not it.
This year.
Yeah.
Remember what I mentioned about AI doing funny things?
This is the go to week.
And then it router push.
Okay.
So, yeah.
It is pushing the week ID.
And that is causing it.
We are noticing everything.
So, everyone knows that it crashes on there.
And as well, when they get to this point.
It works for you.
Okay.
So, yeah.
This is a smidge odd.
See what error is my getting.
A new planner card body.
Is that why it's yelling at me?
No, you watch it at the same code.
Okay.
Did you also do the same way where you had the planner out here rather than, like,
No, I have planner as an index.
Okay.
Let's try this.
And then perhaps this is a bug.
I was trying to be a little cheeky by jumping ahead.
But that may have ultimately been a mistake.
I'm going to go ahead and update these real quick.
Okay.
Great.
Weak.
Wow.
Really doesn't like it.
This is why we debug live.
Okay.
Let me just fix this icon thing.
Then let's make sure we remove all issues that we have.
Where's it getting an icon?
Okay. Got it.
But to be honest at that point, I'm just going to import base icon if I'm going to
solve this and just do base icon and set of icon.
It's name and then sure with height, whatever.
Okay.
So now this.
Oh wait.
What is this?
This does not like it.
Okay. You know what I'm going to do though on the planner.
You planner body.
We're just going to delete this for now.
Okay. So now no errors.
But for some reason, it's still cannot find the page.
For those of you running into it,
I believe somewhere in the hot module reloading.
Something, some wires got crossed.
So if you shut down your server, reboot it,
it's able to reconnect all the dots.
So yeah, some people didn't have that issue.
And then I clearly I was able to duplicate it by accident.
So yeah.
So the good old turnout off and on again.
Save the day.
All right. Excellent. So with that, I think we're almost done.
Actually, we just have one more thing.
And that's this not found page.
And so I'm going to go ahead and just.
So you all know because again, I never.
I'm never going to memorize this.
And I know it's like any of you to ever.
So you know, we look for the docs.
That's what the docs are for.
We are going to search for what they call this like a catch all.
So you see here catch all not found 404 out.
And so the way this works is you actually do a dot dot dot
behind the path.
So if you think about it from a JavaScript perspective,
it is essentially a spread operator.
Saying whatever the heck the path is.
If you can match this at the very, very end,
then go to this thing.
And so in our case, so if we look at our routes.
And then I go ahead and delete this last one.
Now it's reloaded.
Okay.
If I go to my route and this time I'm going to say something funny.
Nothing shows up.
This makes sense because now there's no catch all.
So let's try this again.
Not found move it in.
And again, we want it to be.
So if you think about a catch all again,
it's that asterisk concept.
So you really it's a dynamic property dot dot dot path.
It's really what we're doing.
All right.
It's reloaded.
I think up.
It already did it for me.
How much reloading.
And that's how you'll catch.
Any routes that haven't that aren't able to be matched.
And oh, actually, I guess, you know,
if you're talking about final rerout things.
Since we know for a fact that at least for now,
again, I can always recreate this whenever I want.
This is effectively empty.
Because at this point, I don't foresee a world where I need to manually configure
out.
So I can delete the routes file.
I can delete this import.
To be honest, I don't mind calling it auto routes.
It's kind of explicit.
So this is fine.
But obviously, if you want to just be even more succinct,
you can just do this.
This is fine.
And that is a full refactor.
You didn't have to then update any.
If you've got routed up pushes anywhere.
Nope.
You didn't.
Isn't that so great?
It's amazing.
It's such a nice developer experience.
Yeah.
For me, I can't.
Whenever I'm on a project without it, I'm like,
I have to type the object.
I got to type and then I got to configure it.
It just makes it so much more fun to just try stuff out.
And I feel like that's what a lot of development is.
Creating a faster feedback cycle so that we can try more things.
The more feedback loops we have, the more we can iterate and do cool things.